<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on BlogDA</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on BlogDA</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Energy prices in Italy</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/2024/05/17/energy-prices-in-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/2024/05/17/energy-prices-in-italy/</guid>
      <description>With this very brief post I would like to stress the attention on the electricity prices for the Italian market. The focus is on households and the consumption band is between 2500 KWh and 5000 KWh (according to Eurostat the medium standard household consumption band in Europe).&#xA;Although it is well known the shock brought about by the war in Ukraine on the energy markets in 2022, it is also worth remarking the fact that in Italy we are experiencing a shift towards the free market where the presence of several competitors should guarantee low energy prices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work from home</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/2024/05/03/work-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/2024/05/03/work-from-home/</guid>
      <description>Working from home in EU A picture of the diffusion of the working from home modality during and &amp;lsquo;after&amp;rsquo; the pandemic in EU countries.&#xA;A clear huge revolution in the work organisation, which can not be dismissed as a temporary measure to overcome the Covid-19 pandemic.&#xA;A simple measure gives count of the phenomenon. The average percent of workers (employees) that usually work from home in the following years: 2019, 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IRsmart Project - Main results</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/2023/09/30/irsmart-project-main-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/2023/09/30/irsmart-project-main-results/</guid>
      <description>The present post shows the main results of the IRsmart (Industrial Relations for Smart-Workers in Smart Cities) project. A project led by me UNIFE, co-funded by the European Union and involving the following great partners: from France, Ultra Laborans (ex ASTREES); from Spain, INGENIO; from Italy, IRES Emilia-Romagna; from Poland, Institute of Public Affairs; from Romania, UAIC.&#xA;The project delved into the diffusion of remote working in Europe, during and immediately after the Covid-19 pandemic and its consequences on workers, firms and territoris (cities)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italy: governance</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/2022/08/26/italy-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/2022/08/26/italy-governance/</guid>
      <description>As the national political elections approach (25th of September 2022) it might worth pointing out the Italian situation, compared with other relevant EU countries like France, Germany and Spain, in terms of two governance dimension:&#xA;the rule of law (Rule of Law captures perceptions of the extent to which agents have confidence in and abide by the rules of society, and in particular the quality of contract enforcement, property rights, the police, and the courts, as well as the likelihood of crime and violence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Italy: corruption perception and control</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/2022/08/24/italy-corruption-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/2022/08/24/italy-corruption-perception/</guid>
      <description>As the national political elections approach (25th of September 2022) it might worth pointing out the Italian situation, compared with other relevant EU countries like France, Germany and Spain, in terms of a governance dimension associated to corruption perception and control.&#xA;Here I present two indexes: one coming from the Transparency International organisation (Fig.1) and the other coming from The World Bank (Fig.2) over a period going from 2013 to 2021 (when available).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RdC</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/2022/07/25/rdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/2022/07/25/rdc/</guid>
      <description>A measure of social protection in Italy: Reddito di Cittadinanza (RdC) The RdC, an articulated measure of social protection in Italy, targets the most vulnerable regions.&#xA;This form of &amp;lsquo;basic income&amp;rsquo; is designed as an active policy on the labour market, since it works as an economic support to the family income associated with a path of work and social reintegration, given that the beneficiaries need to be immediately available to train and to work.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
